# MUSTAPHA LATEB

Website: mlateb.github.io | GitHub: mlateb

Email: mustapha.lateb@qmail.com

Adress: Chania, Greece | Phone: 699 499 7057

#### INTRODUCTION

Graduated, both, in **Ecology** and in **Geoinformation**. My research is mainly on Landcover change and forest fire mapping using satellite Remote Sensing and GIS.

Fun of **Data science**, I like to investigate new Image Processing, Machine Learning, Statistics and Timeseries Analysis techniques.

My most used tools are Python and its Geospatial libraries, QGIS, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS and Git.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

 Jan 2017- Current: Researcher at the Geoinformation in Environmental Management departement, Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania MAICh.

During two years I held two positions at Aldaph-NovoNordisk, a global healthcare company:

- Mar 2013-Sep 2013: Energy Steward at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria
- Nov 2011-Feb 2013: Quality Assurance Technician at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2016 current: PhD student, Geoinformation applied to Plant Ecology, Mouloud Mammeri University of Tizi-Ouzou MMTO, Algeria Topic: Multitemporal landcover mapping
- 2013 2016: M. Sc. Degree (2 years), Geoinformation in Environmental Management, MAICh, Greece
  Thesis topic: "Development of an object-based classification model for monitoring treeline shifting, using aerial photography"
- 2011-2014: Magister degree (2 years), Applied Plant Ecology and Environmental Management, UMMTO, Algeria Thesis topic: "Study of oak hybridisation using Geometric Morphometric (Landmark Method)"
- 2006 2011 : *Ingénieur d'Etat (5 years)*, **Plant ecology and Environment** UMMTO, Algeria *Thesis topic*: "Inventory of oak gallings and evaluation their impact on forest stands"
- 2008 2011 : Senior Technician (3 years), Database Management INSFP, Algeria Thesis topic: " Creation of a Dynamic Website "

### ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS

At <u>MAICh</u>, I worked in multicultural and multidisciplinary environment. I was in the organising committee of the two following conferences:

- 38th Annual EARSeL Symposium on Earth Observation Supporting Sustainability Research 9-12 July 2018 Chania, Crete, Greece
- 11th EARSeL Forest Fires SIG Workshop on New Trends in Forest Fire Research Incorporating Big Data and Climate Change Modeling 25-27 September 2017, Chania, GREECE

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Geospatial processing: Python (MITx 6.00.1x certificate) (Rasterio, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, geopandas, Shapely, ...)
- Version controle: Git
- Database: SQL
- Web design:  $\mathsf{HTML}$  ,  $\mathsf{CSS}$ ,  $\mathsf{Markdown}$  Softwares:  $\mathsf{QGIS}$ ,  $\mathsf{eCognition}$ ,  $\mathsf{ArcGIS}$ ,  $\mathsf{ERDAS}$ ,  $\mathsf{MapInfo}$
- Operating systems: Linux & Windows

## LANGUAGES

- Kabyle: Mother tongue
- English: Fluent French: Fluent Arabic: Fluent Greek: Beginner